She can walk down the kind of model this horse, but everybody.
Good job, yeah.
So, Steve, New Year's Warms?
This is actually what your first U.S. art class be.
This is the old traditional uniform.
So, I like it.
Looks good.
I like it.
Yeah.
You like the blue?
Well, I guess I have to sing them because
I don't think they've been in this uniform for probably six or three years.
Oh, no.
Yeah, about 20.
This is actually the uniform.
This is the shirt.
It was good.
That's your uniform.
So, I'll make it a couple of things.
You know, I'll see.
I think, like, if I have also going to presentations or things like that,
that this will look better than the B.D.
Well done, sir.
I'm still not wearing pants.
I like it.
But it is where it shorts.
Yeah.
I love that.
You can sit in the pants.
All right.
I have the fashion parts out of the wig.
We can get on with the real part.
Parts.
You've got the shirt on too.
I don't know.
Yeah.
The implication by our part.
Parts.
Mr. Christian.
Heavenly Father, we're thankful for you and who you are and we're just thankful for the way you bless us and provide for us.
Lord, we're just glad we can come be a part of the business.
Our community and we ask that you give our leaders wisdom and guidance and the decisions they make tonight.
It's in your name we pray.
And remember.
I'd like to lead you to the side of the United States of America.
I'd like to lead you to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation under God and then visible with liberty and justice for God.
And before we're public input, I'm scared of personal experiences.
Number five, presentation discussion.
With presentation from idea tech regarding fiber optic internet service.
John Terry.
Thank you, sir.
I brought James Christolic with me.
Okay.
I'm a told you guys.
I'm at the last meeting that you'd see my little mug again this week.
So here I am, a poem through on that promise.
I introduce myself last time.
I'll do it again.
My name's John Terry with idea tech.
I'm out of Gillesburg, Kansas.
I'm about an hour up the road here in New York County.
And being here means a lot to me.
My wife and I actually were married in Miami, Oklahoma 12 years ago.
June 26th of 2013.
It might be the 28th show where Miami and June, I'm sure.
But it meant a lot to me to find out that idea tech was interested in building Miami.
For that reason and many others.
Being in someone who lives in the four states, I'm excited to see this region grow.
Miami is a perfect opportunity for us.
with this looks a lot like a lot of the other communities that we invest in.
So we're very excited to bring a $10 million private investment here and bring some quality
good pay and jobs with benefits to the region as well.
We've got some affordable eight gigs of medical fiber that we're looking forward to bringing to every home and business.
Not cherry picking.
It'll be available to anybody who wants it.
And we don't have residential contracts.
So that's a good thing.
Obviously people don't like getting tied up by pieces of paper on residential service.
We don't cap that up.
We don't throttle.
I'm no gimmicks.
Just a libert and service month a month that you pay for as long as you're happy with it.
I did turn an apartment on Wednesday of last week with a check and we're looking forward to getting started.
As soon as we get with the city and have a conversation about how to move forward.
James drove three hours down from which and also I knew he's got some things he'd like to say.
Yeah, I know.
Thank you.
James Christolic with ideas.
I've been really kind of looking at my hammer for quite some time.
I know I've had some meetings with a couple of you all.
And really exciting.
You know, when we look at ideas at where we're, where did we come from,
became from a small town of Bealer, Kansas.
1200 people.
We really understood what it means to be left behind.
Rule kind of citizens.
So what we've done is, is throughout the state of Kansas.
We've built out about 130 communities.
All who really didn't have a great option.
And so now we're kind of moving into across the state and looking at some areas that may do have an option,
but they don't have two options.
And we've kind of looked at this area.
It's quite some time.
We've kind of looked at kind of the quapal commerce and even in Miami.
And now we're here.
We're here to say, hey, we want to be able to provide the internet for you all.
Idea tech started is as a senior high school project back in 1999.
We were for four high school students, Daniel Frieson at a dealer.
There was an RFP for Bealer high school abilities computers back in the day when, you know,
the floppy disk computers were out.
And so they were going to get a bid out from a witch at all.
And they convinced the staff that said, hey, can we put an RFP for this as well.
And so the staff said, okay, you guys are high school seniors.
Sure, do you have any backing so they wouldn't got started in the company with $250 each.
To be able to start idea tech.
And they put in that application and they want.
And so for 1999, May, idea tech was formed.
And since then, it's in 1999 to 2007,
and with the college, they started buying up some failing DSL companies because they realized that was kind of going out.
But Bealer Kansas was actually the first city in the state of Kansas have actual full residential fiber connection.
So when you look at Bealer, very midnight community,
they had access better access in some cities like Wichita,
all in bigger cities like Topeka, better in the state of Kansas.
So it's really been our passion to kind of serve these areas.
So we started rule.
So when we look at communities to invest in, we look and say, okay,
what is out there?
What is the opportunity for idea tech to be able to come in and help these residents?
And so when we come in our pricing package, you know,
they start $40.
What sets us different from the competition is when we come into a community or part of the community.
So you're going to see a lot like John said there's some jobs that are coming.
You're going to see local people work in here.
You might see an office here.
Definitely know that you'll be seeing us around.
When we get involved in the community, we get involved.
We invest in the community.
We invest in the chambers.
We invest in projects that really make the city a better place to live.
So we encourage you guys to reach out to ideas.
I understand the city might be building their own infrastructure.
That's okay.
We encourage competition all the time.
We still want to work together and things that we can do.
So you're going to like I said, you've got John down here.
You've got myself up here from time to time as well.
So just wanted to kind of talk about that and answer any type of questions that you may have.
And I'll let John kind of see if there's anything else I missed.
Yeah, there's one thing that James didn't mention that I think is important in a community like my
him and in a region like Southeast.
We participate in what's called the Equal Access Program.
And what that is, is it's through the federal government, if you are a lifeline participant,
basically if you're on reduced school lunches, if you're on a fixed income, we offer a package that you can afford.
I believe it's 2499 a month.
Yeah, exactly.
So yeah, we do that because we understand there's different income levels throughout everywhere we go.
Not everybody can afford the same prices or neighbors, but we don't want to leave anybody behind.
So we participate in that program and so we do the same thing here by him.
We partner with school districts to let them know that when they're getting their kids enrolled,
and here's an extra thing that they can't enroll.
So some counties, some states, they have, you know, laws can't be in there during open enrollment,
but they take those packets and hand those to the families at enrollment.
So we do that.
We'll be doing the same thing here as well.
So like I said, we're going to get really much involved in the booster and everything within the community of schools.
But that's just one thing that we want to do to help families and we understand.
It comes.
They're very tight right now and we don't think that rock and should be something that you can't afford.
Since for us guys, or anything else that we can discuss about the products, you're going to offer as a just internet.
You're going to offer phone or you're going to offer a TV.
And it would be just internet and phone service.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's exactly.
We don't do TV.
We used to do TV back in the early 2000s, but what we've learned is the rise, the cost of rising TV to be able to subscribe.
If you give that, it's just not our model.
We'd say, if you have a good internet access, you should be able to stream.
And so we actually teach people how to stream.
We do informational meetings.
So when we come into the community, we teach people what is fiber, what exactly do I need to do to connect to fiber, what speed is best for me.
And job means you're like no contract.
So when we come in and we talk to a family and they just might be themselves and their husband and all they do is they maybe watch TV or they got through cell phones.
We kind of put them in that and say, hey, you can start here.
It's okay.
You need more work and it's pumping up later.
you're streaming but with phones for businesses but we also do analog lines well so somebody
has a home phone line they can't connect that and work that number home.
See the inputs.
So you guys do fiber to curb or fiber to home?
Sorry, fiber to curb or fiber to home life.
What's your connection?
Fiber to the home.
Yeah.
Every home or business system, subscribe to get the strand of the last fiber to the other.
So we do our best not to overbuild our network because you know everything is off-road.
I always make jokes, we go into communities, they won't call you if their speed is a love
that they will call you.
And so we take pride of making sure our network is sustained and it will be eight up
right now.
Yes, that's what we're at.
We've got special technology that allows that.
We've seen that in more markets and write some people say that's what we're going to
kill right now.
Which could be the case but you know, five years ago, 20 my five was considered acceptable now.
It's 100 my five what it used to be.
So eight gig and technology is there so it's more AI and more type of things come out.
People have that bandwidth, here again, they have that option and we have those router
motors that are up to those eight gig.
You get some people that are the best and then you have some people that we will provide a piece
of my services as well.
So if you're not tech savvy, if you're like I really don't know, we have staff on train that
can actually remote it and fix and diagnose those issues for them and then we have some that
are very good at fixing it.
That's why you have their choice to get a huge room.
So if someone comes to the motor or the router, that's something they lease, but they keep
they have the option to do that.
So when we have our freedom package, so what that comes with that is that piece of mine serves
like where you like, I just wanted to work in a bit breaks, I want to call you and I want to
get fixed and they don't want to necessarily deal with anything that's sort of what comes
in my face and the router, they can unplug it and plug it back in and when it comes to
actual troubleshooting it, they're like, I'm just not exactly that's what that comes with.
So there's no service charge for a set of technicians out there to get that fixed.
That's included in that moment.
But that's an add-on that you can.
And if you do happen to have your own router, we'll adapt it to the service.
Yeah.
And I apologize we had a presentation like a thing that we can sweeten to email that over to as well so you
can look at that and it breaks down and writes what we call freedom, why, why, why, so you can
see exactly what that is.
So if they have that package, then there's no charge for truck rolls or anything, that's correct.
That's it.
If you have your own modem and that's a mess, come out there to truck roll and charge them.
Yeah, it is.
And so like yes, you are 100% correct.
Well you understand any time you provide her in the ground, there's always this case that you
got to work out.
And so we have technicians in the town and so they're there, we can get that done, we'll get that done.
We try to make sure when we go into the house.
Or we'll talk about, and then go in, they'll check the connection of each room, allow them how one allows you in that room to make sure you have good connectivity.
If you don't, you need to have an access point, you know, we can have those as well, some people like the B.O.E.s now we can see it.
So, there's lots of technical things to go into that, but people have to have hard-wired connections, so we've seen a lot of that.
So, we have those problems.
One thing that's important, I think, to mention on the subject of travel shooting, too, is that we,
all of our travel shooting, all of our support is in-house, which means that when you call when you have an issue, you're going to talk to somebody from this street.
We don't contract out support calls, so even if it's something basic and minor, unplug it and plug it in the router, you're going to talk to somebody that you can understand,
who can understand you.
What is your, what is your design look like from an infrastructure perspective?
So, like, for example, fiber is pretty notorious for if this guy digs a hole in his jar and he cuts a fiber line, then the whole area is out.
Is that something that would exist with your kind of design?
I haven't personally seen the holes I haven't seen that.
I haven't seen the full design, but I don't think so.
I think because basically everything is broken down into separate bolts and separate flower pots, if somebody hits, if somebody hits the main backbone,
I'm sure.
We don't know what to take an excavating machine or something to take that out to it, but if somebody's out digging in their yard, it's their fiber line,
and it's going to their house, that is something that would exist.
And maybe that specific pedestal that he's talking about might be able to view three months more on that one.
So, yeah, good effect.
Those are the few homes.
And you guys looking at doing a lot of underground or overhead.
The design that we turned in is all underground.
Now, there may be a few instances depending on what once we get a conversation, you don't want to find out if you guys have services that are just jam packed into this area,
where we have a design, we can either cross you across the road, or if it makes more sense, we can work with the city on a full attachment agreement to go aerial,
whatever the case may be, and we've seen that for some cities like, hey, we prefer you be on the poles, because of this, you know,
infrastructure might be useful, the health skills may come.
Also, we've seen some cities saying, hey, we have ice storms.
This way, it just kind of depends on what city, like Johnson, I believe this, I guess this is an underground design building.
Some of them are hybrid.
They'll be direct barrier, or board, or if it would be board.
And you know, there's some instances where the pedestals and bolts in the ground, where you'll have many experts on some excavates to add.
Typically, the process now, the one that we did in Maxar Springs was an underground building, the hotboard, or the head of board, with shells, to basically cite everything that's in.
who works in utilities and knows that I don't care how good your tracer wire is and how dedicated your locator is
Every now and then you're going to get a little bit off path
So you got to have inspectors go out and inspect once the job's done
So people with your ginger put back like they're supposed to be
Yeah, because we'll be called
We have a really high standard for our contractors if you talk to shelling up their backs or springs
I'm not going to say here until you there weren't issues it was an underground bill with an underground bill
You're going to hit some things that said shelling just today when I was talking to those who are
Marking about how Roman the contractor supervisor in the field. He's like man this guy's been excellent to work
But if we have phone call from residents and they came through your last week and I'm still I don't have hey and straw and seat down in my in my yard
He calls Roman Roman goes out there and takes care of the problem
But one thing we ask especially as construction begins is is to not just communicate with contractor but let us know
That bit like what's going on because there can be times where you're like well, we're dealing directly with them
So you know, we've gone and I we deal with a lot of different kinds of clients will guide them through our customer portal
We're great to take it, but yeah, we understand you've got to make a line
And they need to stand who makes it because we've got to work for a small town
So small town reputation there for things to us
So we'll definitely be able to get there is concerned and during the pre-instruction meeting we'll have the contractor
Field supervisor he's going to be on the ground. We will have our project manager is basically going to end in myself and in that contractor
Supervisor who is the first one in contact. You should be fixing issues right now not tomorrow
Next week we get to he's unavailable or something's not done since satisfaction through him. Then you'll talk to our
Project manager will ensure that
Appreciate it
Number six, coin flows
Super
Hi
I'm being played in place for bands auto group
What's your second
Double
Hi
Joe, hi
Farron type, Farron type, Farron type, Farron type. I'm seeing minutes from the October 7, 2020 by Rader Eden
What's your proof?
He said
So what?
Joe's hi
Farron type, Farron type
Hi, seven other new businesses if any which is residents supposed to be this agenda
Hey staff reports
There you get something that so I so I am on the storm water staff report key 3 205 be population control staff report
September 2025 and see solid waste
Just leave these out. There's no easier for us to read. Yeah, just we got the new what would you say new granicas software and it's just the way it plays it out
So the population control
That's a pollution
I'll say population control
Sorry
We're giving you that a long time
I had a lady miss me she lives out on
17th self-western thing about sea
17th
You guys like have a schedule where you go and how you go or any time out streets we've been
I'm talking about the boats bring the mosquito
Which I know that's over now, but oh
So pollution control for a fast mayor pollution control is like sewer so the sanitary sewer system so it's like the tolerance
Yeah, sorry, my brain let's focus on that one
Right, it's over now, but she was asking me if there was sometimes schedule and so I'm sure there is but I don't know what it is
So that was the way off on all that what's next
I do have a question so over by the Indian police station
I think it was posted online, but there was like a water issue on the corner here
Like it was just come out of the road
There's also one on Bay Street, which is on the other side of the police station
And I just wanted to bring that to your attention because I've noticed it a couple of days
And then I went on a walk and I saw it and I was like that's like actively coming out
Okay, I should probably tell there
I know
Okay, cool
I can trust my communications
No sir
This meeting will be continued from Cal State Regimeo staff from the purpose of the executive session at the completion of the regular meeting